let questions = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Developer of ‘C’ language is ______________.",
    answer: "a.) Dennis Richie",
    options: [
      "a.) Dennis Richie",
      "b.) Ken Thompson",
      "c.) Bill Gates",
      "d.) Peter Norton"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question: "C language developed in ________________.",
    answer: "b.) 1972",
    options: [
      "a.) 1970",
      "b.) 1972",
      "c.) 1976",
      "d.) 1980"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "C is ______ level language.",
    answer: "b.) Low",
    options: [
      "a.) High",
      "b.) Low",
      "c.) Middle",
      "d.) Machine"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question: "C is available for which OS?",
    answer: "d.) All of above",
    options: [
      "a.) DOS",
      "b.) Windows",
      "c.) Unix",
      "d.) All of above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Which symbol is used for pre-processor statement?",
    answer: "b.) #",
    options: [
      "a.) !",
      "b.) #",
      "c.) ~",
      "d.) ;"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Which of the following is a scalar data type?",
    answer: "a.) Float",
    options: [
      "a.) Float",
      "b.) Union",
      "c.) Array",
      "d.) Pointer"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Which of the following are tokens in C?",
    answer: "d.) All of above",
    options: [
      "a.) Keywords",
      "b.) Variables",
      "c.) Constants",
      "d.) All of above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "Which is the valid range of “int” data type?",
    answer: "b.) -32768 to +32767",
    options: [
      "a.) 0 to 256",
      "b.) -32768 to +32767",
      "c.) -32767 to +32768",
      "d.) No particular range"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Which symbol is used to terminate a statement?",
    answer: "d.) ;",
    options: [
      "a.) !",
      "b.) #",
      "c.) ~",
      "d.) ;"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "Which escape sequence character is a line terminator?",
    answer: "d.) \\n",
    options: [
      "a.) \\a",
      "b.) \\b",
      "c.) \\m",
      "d.) \\n"
    ]
  },

  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "Which escape sequence character is used to beep from speaker?",
    answer: "a.) \\a",
    options: [
      "a.) \\a",
      "b.) \\b",
      "c.) \\m",
      "d.) \\n"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "Character constants should be enclosed between ____________.",
    answer: "c.) Both A and B",
    options: [
      "a.) Single Quotes",
      "b.) Double Quotes",
      "c.) Both A and B",
      "d.) None of these"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "String constants should be enclosed between ____________.",
    answer: "b.) Double Quotes",
    options: [
      "a.) Single Quotes",
      "b.) Double Quotes",
      "c.) Both A and B",
      "d.) None of these"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "Which of the following is invalid?",
    answer: "c.) ‘a’",
    options: [
      "a.) ‘ ’",
      "b.) “ ”",
      "c.) ‘a’",
      "d.) ‘abc’"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "The maximum length of a variable in C is ______________.",
    answer: "d.) 64",
    options: [
      "a.) 8",
      "b.) 16",
      "c.) 32",
      "d.) 64"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 16,
    question: "The maximum size of ‘float’ variable is ________________.",
    answer: "c.) 4 bytes",
    options: [
      "a.) 1 byte",
      "b.) 2 bytes",
      "c.) 4 bytes",
      "d.) 8 bytes"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 17,
    question: "The maximum size of ‘double’ variable is _______________.",
    answer: "d.) 8 bytes",
    options: [
      "a.) 1 byte",
      "b.) 2 bytes",
      "c.) 4 bytes",
      "d.) 8 bytes"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 18,
    question: "A declaration of float a; double b; occupies ________ of memory.",
    answer: "d.) 12 bytes",
    options: [
      "a.) 1 byte",
      "b.) 6 bytes",
      "c.) 10 bytes",
      "d.) 12 bytes"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 19,
    question: "The size of a string variable is __________.",
    answer: "d.) Not specific",
    options: [
      "a.) 1 byte",
      "b.) 10 bytes",
      "c.) 20 bytes",
      "d.) Not specific"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 20,
    question: "Which is an example of compounded assignment statement?",
    answer: "c.) a=b=c",
    options: [
      "a.) a=5",
      "b.) a=b",
      "c.) a=b=c",
      "d.) a+=10"
    ]
  },
];